# **BENJAMIN FOLKS**

E: <u>bfolks2@gmail.com</u> • M: (630)-217-5872 1143 W Wrightwood Ave #1F, Chicago, IL 60614

bfolks2.pythonanywhere.com, www.benfolks.com, https://github.com/bfolks2

### **AEROSPACE-SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Multi-faceted engineer with experience working on project teams in numerous fast-paced environments. Aims to combine Aerospace Engineering Degree, software development experience gained in professional environments, and real-world aviation experience as an *FAA Certified Instrument-Rated Pilot*.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Back-end: Python, Django/DRF, VB.NET, VBA

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES5, ES6), Ember.js, ¡Query

Other: SolidWorks 3D CAD, Esprit CAD/CAM, Selenium, S3, Git, GitHub

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### RedShelf • Chicago, IL • January 2018 - Present

Web development company providing digital content for educational institutions

#### **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

- Work within an Agile software development team collaborating with product managers and UX/UI designers, using SCRUM methodology
- Optimize Python tasks to be run daily that integrate the internal database with external API's
- Construct unit, integration, and acceptance (Selenium) tests to deliver testable and maintainable code
- Build back-end REST API to handle all requests from an internal, front-end Ember.js application
- Design API endpoints allowing external users access to corresponding read only or read/write eCommerce operations, based on varying levels of Authentication
- Create email service integrating internal database models with live SendGrid web updates
- Build and maintain SSO user authentication service based on SHA256 hashing algorithm

#### AdThrill • Chicago, IL • December 2017 - Present, (Part-Time)

Start-up website for users to watch and rate advertisements (adthrill-prod.herokuapp.com)

# **Lead Software Engineer**

- Compile/analyze all user-response data and allow businesses to view their corresponding results via graphical representations on a web-based UI and/or downloadable CSV files
- Integrate with PayPal API to support live user payouts and details inquiries
- Deployed the first live production version of the site using Heroku, with continuous increments

# DP Technology - ESPRIT • Rosemont, IL • July 2012 - December 2017

Developer and supplier of computer-aided manufacturing (CAM) software for CNC machine tools

### Senior Manufacturing/Software Engineer

- Determine processes and tooling necessary for manufacturing aerospace and automotive parts
- Produce time studies and functional programs for CNC mills, lathes, and multitasking machine tools
- Create technical designs and assemblies of dynamic machine models within SolidWorks 3D CAD
- Plan and create VB.NET/VBA applications within the ESPRIT API to increase machining automation
- Travel onsite to aerospace and US government clients to oversee technical projects, including NASA Glenn, Woodward Inc, Northstar Aerospace, Tinker AFB

### **EDUCATION**

BS Aerospace Engineering • University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign • 2011 FAA Certified Private Pilot - Instrument Rating Certified SolidWorks Mechanical Design Professional Certified Professional Scrum Master I